<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life on d2h.net: flotsam, jetsam, &amp; lagan</title><link>https://d2h.net/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in life on d2h.net: flotsam, jetsam, &amp; lagan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Dirk Husemann — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 22:31:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d2h.net/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>shipping forecast</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-03-07-shipping-forecast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 22:31:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-03-07-shipping-forecast/</guid><description>having just updated our squeezebox radios i re-found the BBC iplayer plugin. it’s been lingering in depths of the squeezebox radio menus for ages, i guess, but i had never really checked it out. while waiting for @jmdhh to return i decided to give the iplayer plugin a spin.
for some reasons i narrowed in on BBC4 and encountered old friends such as “the now show” (which i regularly listen to via their podcast) or less known shows such as the intriguingly named “life: an idiot’s guide” (need to check that one out).</description></item><item><title>a time trip to the 1950s</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-22-a-time-trip-to-the-1950s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 14:58:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-22-a-time-trip-to-the-1950s/</guid><description>even though the place we live at here in switzerland has a rather rural character — there are several livestock markets throughout the year down at the station square, very few regions regularly vote more conservative than ours — einsiedeln has a surprising cultural live. one of the driving forces is the chaernehus, which several times a year hosts cabaret, an exhibition, and stages a play.
this year’s play is kino etzel — which @jmdhh and i went to see tonight.</description></item><item><title>smells &amp; memory</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-16-smells-memory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 23:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-16-smells-memory/</guid><description>the other day @jmdhh and i were out shopping. while i was waiting at one of the shops i was “hit” by a smell of coffee — and immediately taken back to the apartment of my grandmother in the late 60s, early 70s. she lived in bremerhaven, one of the german sea ports, and had a penchant for coffee.
her apartment always smelled of coffee in a certain way — the smell of coffee emanating from that shop at which i was waiting for @jmdhh must have hit my olfactory memory at just the right spot and triggered that flashback to my childhood.</description></item><item><title>some more pseudo HDR experiments</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-31-some-more-pseudo-hdr-experiments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 07:46:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-31-some-more-pseudo-hdr-experiments/</guid><description>during sunday’s #twallfahrt i managed to take a couple of 5-step bracketed pictures, two of which i think produced some interesting results. the first one is the view from etzel pass towards einsiedeln:
at first i thought that it looks a bit weird, then i realized (and on my way home looked at the clouds with “different eyes”) that it does look like that.
the second one is a classical, an in-door shot in the church of the monastery of einsiedeln1:</description></item><item><title>world’s first twitter wallfahrt!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-29-worlds-first-twitter-wallfahrt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 20:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-29-worlds-first-twitter-wallfahrt/</guid><description>9:10 — ms d and i arrive at einsiedeln railway station, all kitted out in our walking gear, ready to go. walking past the train we spot our fellow pilgrims. yep, pilgrims: we are on our way to the starting point of the world’s first twitter pilgrimage, the #twallfahrt1 from pfäffikon to einsiedeln. in the train we meet @decolores1, @konzertharfe, @sempreincorsaa also ready to go on the #twallfahrt. just before the train is about to depart at 9:13 we are joined at the last second by @abtmartin — good thing, too, as he is supposed to lead us on our pilgrimage i’m looking forward to the first twitter pilgrimage which is at the same time my first pilgrimage on foot (last year’s pilgrimage was by bus, which somehow gives it a different twist, i think).</description></item><item><title>how my grandfather created an island…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-16-how-my-grandfather-created-an-island/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 18:24:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-16-how-my-grandfather-created-an-island/</guid><description>my grandfather was a sea-faring man.1
my grandfather was a sea-faring man, and, what is more, he helped create an island… an island that is still visible today.
he was employed by the North German Lloyd aka Norddeutscher Lloyd as an officer, his last ship was the steamship goslar. shortly before the outbreak of world war II the goslar was on its way back to germany and had just passed the panama canal when adolf the terrible declared war on poland.</description></item><item><title>d2h.net now mobile friendly</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-d2h-net-now-mobile-friendly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 20:43:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-d2h-net-now-mobile-friendly/</guid><description>thanks to the excellent wordpress mobile pack wordpress plugin i’m pleased to announce that d2h.net is now mobile enabled: if you visit it on your android or iDon’t, err, iPhone you’ll get a mobile browser-friendly version of our web site. also, http://m.d2h.net/ will take you to the mobile version directly as well.
oh, and you might have noticed, i’ve re-organized the site structure slightly, the blog is now directly at the root of the site.</description></item><item><title>friday evening rucola salmon salad</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-friday-evening-rucola-salmon-salad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-friday-evening-rucola-salmon-salad/</guid><description>easy salad:
about 125g rucola leaves about 80-100g smoked salmon 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 teaspoons of whole-grained mustard salt lemon juice cut or shred the salmon into little pieces. wash the rucola leaves in a colander and shake off the excessive water. mix the rucola, and the salmon pieces in a bowl. add the oil and the mustard along with a couple of squirts of the lemon juice.</description></item></channel></rss>