<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>d2h.net: flotsam, jetsam, &amp; lagan</title><link>https://d2h.net/</link><description>Recent content on d2h.net: flotsam, jetsam, &amp; lagan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Dirk Husemann — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 21:17:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d2h.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>githubbing</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2022-01-19-githubbing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 21:17:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2022-01-19-githubbing/</guid><description>I recently read the excellent essay my first impressions of web3 by moxie marlinspike, and one of the observations he is making is1
People don’t want to run their own servers, and never will.
Running your own server is fun and very instructional &amp;mdash; for geeks like us…
…for a time…
…after about 20 years or so you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it all, done it all, tried it all, met all the script kiddies in your logs, evaded them by moving your SSH server port out of harm&amp;rsquo;s way (not that you were using password-based ssh accounts to begin with, it was just so annoying to see them try the same thing over and over again, no creativity really, come on…), dito for the attack attempts on your nginx server (again, easily foiled, by using a handful of fail2ban rules).</description></item><item><title>About…</title><link>https://d2h.net/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:07:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/about/</guid><description>Welcome to my blog, d2h.net. Here you will stuff that I find interesting, useful, or noteworthy for some reason or other &amp;mdash; in short, stuff the cat dragged in, or the sea delivered to our doorsteps.
This blog is built using
hugo, emacs, a derivative of the smigle hugo theme, the computer modern typewriter font, and the special elite typewriter font, and is hosted via github.
Responsible contact:</description></item><item><title>building emacs for macos</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-12-27-emacs-for-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 14:53:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-12-27-emacs-for-macos/</guid><description>my copy of emacs installed through homebrew was acting up: everytime i tried to click the &amp;ldquo;markdown&amp;rdquo; menu when editing a markdown&amp;rsquo;ed text file, emacs would terminate rather abruptly (aka crash). decidedly not nice.
so: try to reinstall… a couple of hours later this is the recipe that worked for me:
&amp;gt; brew install --with-modern-icon --without-spacemacs-icon --with-mailutils --with-jansson --HEAD emacs-plus followed by
option-cmd dragging the generated /usr/local/opt/emacs-plus/Emacs.app to /Applications, and allowing Emacs full-disk access macos security setings for emacs</description></item><item><title>automated hugo</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-06-14-gitea-drone-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 08:26:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-06-14-gitea-drone-hugo/</guid><description>Inspired by Evan Brown&amp;rsquo;s post Hugo on the go I decided to follow pretty much the same route &amp;mdash; with a couple of twists.
In a nutshell Evan has set up a continuous integration chain for his hugo based website. The workflow is as follows:
create the new hugo post on whatever device you want commit the post and push to github github triggers the continuous integration service travis travis regenerates the static web site travis deploys the static web site Where Evan is using github, travis, and S3 I wanted to go the self-hosted route.</description></item><item><title>Full Circle</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-05-19-switching-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 16:53:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-05-19-switching-to-hugo/</guid><description>OK, I&amp;rsquo;m back to where I started, blog-wise: statically generated content. The first incarnation of d2h.net was using an emacs generated blog, this time round I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with using hugo.
The workflow is a bit different now from back then: content is contained in a self-hosted gitea instance, which is feeding into a self-hosted drone instance, all docker-ized.
The hugo theme is not quite there yet, expect changes 😀</description></item><item><title>shipping forecast</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-03-07-shipping-forecast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 22:31:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-03-07-shipping-forecast/</guid><description>having just updated our squeezebox radios i re-found the BBC iplayer plugin. it’s been lingering in depths of the squeezebox radio menus for ages, i guess, but i had never really checked it out. while waiting for @jmdhh to return i decided to give the iplayer plugin a spin.
for some reasons i narrowed in on BBC4 and encountered old friends such as “the now show” (which i regularly listen to via their podcast) or less known shows such as the intriguingly named “life: an idiot’s guide” (need to check that one out).</description></item><item><title>a time trip to the 1950s</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-22-a-time-trip-to-the-1950s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 14:58:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-22-a-time-trip-to-the-1950s/</guid><description>even though the place we live at here in switzerland has a rather rural character — there are several livestock markets throughout the year down at the station square, very few regions regularly vote more conservative than ours — einsiedeln has a surprising cultural live. one of the driving forces is the chaernehus, which several times a year hosts cabaret, an exhibition, and stages a play.
this year’s play is kino etzel — which @jmdhh and i went to see tonight.</description></item><item><title>smells &amp; memory</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-16-smells-memory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 23:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-16-smells-memory/</guid><description>the other day @jmdhh and i were out shopping. while i was waiting at one of the shops i was “hit” by a smell of coffee — and immediately taken back to the apartment of my grandmother in the late 60s, early 70s. she lived in bremerhaven, one of the german sea ports, and had a penchant for coffee.
her apartment always smelled of coffee in a certain way — the smell of coffee emanating from that shop at which i was waiting for @jmdhh must have hit my olfactory memory at just the right spot and triggered that flashback to my childhood.</description></item><item><title>recipe: slow-roasted pork butt (blade)</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-07-recipe-slow-roasted-pork-butt-blade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 19:10:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-07-recipe-slow-roasted-pork-butt-blade/</guid><description>meat:
1kg pork butt (blade) crust:
1 glove garlic teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons italian herb mixture 1 teaspoon sweet paprika 3 tablespoons olive oil freshly ground pepper 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar (aceto balsamico) pre-heat the oven to 80–90°C
wash the pork and dry it with kitchen tissue. incise the pork butt all around in a diagonally criss-crossing pattern.
strip the garlic glove, place it together with the teaspoon of salt in a mortar and crush it with the pestle until you end up with a smooth paste.</description></item><item><title>the joys of creative commons licenses</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-02-the-joys-of-creative-commons-licenses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 15:36:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-02-the-joys-of-creative-commons-licenses/</guid><description>i’m in the process of re-working both this blog and my photo site. for the photo site i’ve switched from zenphoto to jalbum — zenphoto didn’t really offer any decent support for displaying geo-tagged pictures, had at the point in time of switching too many security issues for my taste, and didn’t have such a slick looking theme as jalbum’s turtle skin.
for a couple of sub-albums i wanted to make use of the background music feature offered by the turtle skin.</description></item><item><title>@jmdhh admiring the views…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-07-05-jmdhh-admiring-the-views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 18:57:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-07-05-jmdhh-admiring-the-views/</guid><description>at the beginning of june @jmdhh and i spent two fantastic weeks in the english lake district — one of our walks took us up on top of silver how. the photo below shows @jmdhh enjoying the wonderful landscape and views, all of them at once it seems.
jQuery(document).ready(function(){jQuery(&amp;quot;#848a11e54a625663&amp;quot;).photoNav({id:&amp;ldquo;848a11e54a625663&amp;rdquo;,mode:&amp;ldquo;drag&amp;rdquo;,popup:&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo;,animate:&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;});});</description></item><item><title>recipe: vampire ears tortilla with cherry tomato chutney</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-06-13-recipe-vampire-ears-tortilla-with-cherry-tomato-chutney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 19:22:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-06-13-recipe-vampire-ears-tortilla-with-cherry-tomato-chutney/</guid><description>tortilla1 ingredients:
300g potatoes 140g dried tomatoes in olive oil (aka vampire ears) 40g pitted black olives 5 large eggs clove of garlic 2 + 1 tablespoons olive oil chutney ingredients:
200g cherry tomatoes 1 tablespoon olive oil 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar 1/2 teaspoon sage 2 pinches basil 1 pinch sugar salt pepper start with making the chutney: wash the cherry tomatoes and quarter them. heat the olive oil in a small pan and add the quartered tomatoes, then add the rest of the ingredients.</description></item><item><title>panorama picture experiment</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-01-03-panorama-picture-experiment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 19:16:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-01-03-panorama-picture-experiment/</guid><description>last saturday mrs d and i did a snow shoe hike from alpthal stei up to hochstuckli and then across to biberegg. the views were fantastic, the snow was good prompted by mrs d, i tried my hand at taking a set of pictures to assemble as a panorama later.1 here’s the result (you can use the mouse to drag the picture around):
jQuery(document).ready(function(){jQuery(&amp;quot;#cd03e9de8d63dba5&amp;quot;).photoNav({id:&amp;ldquo;cd03e9de8d63dba5&amp;rdquo;,mode:&amp;ldquo;drag&amp;rdquo;,popup:&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo;,animate:&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;});});
i stitched it together using hugin — i’m quite pleased with it let’s see how it turns out as a 120cm wide print.</description></item><item><title>some more pseudo HDR experiments</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-31-some-more-pseudo-hdr-experiments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 07:46:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-31-some-more-pseudo-hdr-experiments/</guid><description>during sunday’s #twallfahrt i managed to take a couple of 5-step bracketed pictures, two of which i think produced some interesting results. the first one is the view from etzel pass towards einsiedeln:
at first i thought that it looks a bit weird, then i realized (and on my way home looked at the clouds with “different eyes”) that it does look like that.
the second one is a classical, an in-door shot in the church of the monastery of einsiedeln1:</description></item><item><title>world’s first twitter wallfahrt!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-29-worlds-first-twitter-wallfahrt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 20:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-29-worlds-first-twitter-wallfahrt/</guid><description>9:10 — ms d and i arrive at einsiedeln railway station, all kitted out in our walking gear, ready to go. walking past the train we spot our fellow pilgrims. yep, pilgrims: we are on our way to the starting point of the world’s first twitter pilgrimage, the #twallfahrt1 from pfäffikon to einsiedeln. in the train we meet @decolores1, @konzertharfe, @sempreincorsaa also ready to go on the #twallfahrt. just before the train is about to depart at 9:13 we are joined at the last second by @abtmartin — good thing, too, as he is supposed to lead us on our pilgrimage i’m looking forward to the first twitter pilgrimage which is at the same time my first pilgrimage on foot (last year’s pilgrimage was by bus, which somehow gives it a different twist, i think).</description></item><item><title>mucking around with pseudo HDRs</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-28-mucking-around-with-pseudo-hdrs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 19:53:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-28-mucking-around-with-pseudo-hdrs/</guid><description>it’s taken a long time, but i finally managed to upload the pictures of our lake district vacation (back in may, yes…) to our photo website, the 50mm-traveller. for most of the pictures i used the exposure bracketing mode of my D700 (i.e., one picture taken at normal exposure, one a full stop below and the third a full stop above) together with the high-speed setting (5 pictures per second).</description></item><item><title>swiss conservatives: annex regions surrounding switzerland!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-06-12-swiss-conservatives-annex-regions-surrounding-switzerland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 09:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-06-12-swiss-conservatives-annex-regions-surrounding-switzerland/</guid><description>yesterday’s tagesanzeiger report on a parliamentary motion of the swiss conservatives right-wing, nationalist party SVP to prepare the annexation of all regions surrounding switzerland — no, today’s not the first of april.
interesting.
as the tagesanzeiger rightly observes that would add about 10 million germans to the population (plus almost another million german speaking citizens of alsace, vorarlberg, &amp;amp; bolzano) — just a couple of months ago the SVP, never afraid of playing the lowest available instruments of fear, uncertainty, and doubt, staged a campaign claiming that the ETH was being overtaken by german professors (skillfully representing sliced statistics to “prove” their point).</description></item><item><title>how my grandfather created an island…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-16-how-my-grandfather-created-an-island/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 18:24:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-16-how-my-grandfather-created-an-island/</guid><description>my grandfather was a sea-faring man.1
my grandfather was a sea-faring man, and, what is more, he helped create an island… an island that is still visible today.
he was employed by the North German Lloyd aka Norddeutscher Lloyd as an officer, his last ship was the steamship goslar. shortly before the outbreak of world war II the goslar was on its way back to germany and had just passed the panama canal when adolf the terrible declared war on poland.</description></item><item><title>in the lake district again…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-09-in-the-lake-district-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 20:26:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-09-in-the-lake-district-again/</guid><description>after a long day on the train — starting with the 8:43 ICE International train from cologne to brussels, then the Eurostar to london st pancras, followed by the virgin pendolino from london euston (yep, a short walk from there) to oxenholme lake district, and, the last train for today, the First Penine 185 class service to windermere — we have finally arrived at the riverside hotel in ambleside.
the riverside is a small hotel run by david and brenda milne a bit outside ambleside, right next to the river rothay on the quiet under loughrigg lane leading from ambleside to rydal.</description></item><item><title>switzerland — behind the scenes…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-12-29-switzerland-behind-the-scenes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 21:07:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-12-29-switzerland-behind-the-scenes/</guid><description>ever wondered what happens behind the scenes of touristic switzerland? ever wanted to know how the swiss manage to present one of the most beautiful places on earth in such impeccable order? ever interested in the music that drives the swiss?1
wonder no more: here’s a rare behind the scenes look at switzerland:
now you know the true story… well, some of them… ↩</description></item><item><title>d2h.net now mobile friendly</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-d2h-net-now-mobile-friendly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 20:43:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-d2h-net-now-mobile-friendly/</guid><description>thanks to the excellent wordpress mobile pack wordpress plugin i’m pleased to announce that d2h.net is now mobile enabled: if you visit it on your android or iDon’t, err, iPhone you’ll get a mobile browser-friendly version of our web site. also, http://m.d2h.net/ will take you to the mobile version directly as well.
oh, and you might have noticed, i’ve re-organized the site structure slightly, the blog is now directly at the root of the site.</description></item><item><title>friday evening rucola salmon salad</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-friday-evening-rucola-salmon-salad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-friday-evening-rucola-salmon-salad/</guid><description>easy salad:
about 125g rucola leaves about 80-100g smoked salmon 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 teaspoons of whole-grained mustard salt lemon juice cut or shred the salmon into little pieces. wash the rucola leaves in a colander and shake off the excessive water. mix the rucola, and the salmon pieces in a bowl. add the oil and the mustard along with a couple of squirts of the lemon juice.</description></item><item><title>kells, tara, airport, trinity college, chilling out</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-22-kells-tara-airport-trinity-college-chilling-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 20:58:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-22-kells-tara-airport-trinity-college-chilling-out/</guid><description>the last day of our irish pilgrimage! after another good breakfast at the newgrange hotel we pack once more and enter our pilgrims bus — which this morning has grown in size: morris, our excellent driver, swapped our smaller bus yesterday evening for a bigger one as he’s going to pick up a group of 50 at dublin airport right after dropping us off.
the final “building blocks” of our pilgrimage are kells and the hill of tara.</description></item><item><title>a walk through pittoresque boyne valley, time travel, monasterboice, &amp; the hill of slane</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-21-a-walk-through-pittoresque-boyne-valley-time-travel-monasterboice-slaine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 20:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-21-a-walk-through-pittoresque-boyne-valley-time-travel-monasterboice-slaine/</guid><description>mrs d and i slept surprisingly well this night, given the fact that one of the main thorough-fares passes the hotel just a couple of meters away.1 breakfast is efficient and good and the waitresses are actually quite friendly and even know about gluten-free food for mrs j.2
the weather has become rather irish: it’s raining when we set off for a walk in the boyne valley, and it’s treating us to several showers on the otherwise rather pittoresque walk.</description></item><item><title>the burren, limestone pavement, clonmacnoise, &amp; an almost secret birthday</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-20-limestone-pavement-an-almost-secret-birthday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 20:21:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-20-limestone-pavement-an-almost-secret-birthday/</guid><description>after a rather good night and an equally good and relaxed breakfast1 at hotel doolin we pack once more and embark on the long trip across ireland, going from the atlantic west coast all the way to navan. the weather is not as good as it was yesterday with clouds covering most of the sky.
we don’t just go to navan directly but instead take the scenic route. our first stop is at burren national park, the smallest of the 6 national parks in ireland and part of the larger area the burren: a karst landscape exhibiting the typical karst limestone pavement and also host for a number of megalithic tombs and portal dolmens — rather impressive.</description></item><item><title>listowel, shannon river ferry, lahinch, sunday lunch, cliffs of moher, live music at doolin</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-19-listowel-shannon-river-ferry-lahinch-sunday-lunch-cliffs-of-moher-live-music-at-doolinrimage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 21:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-19-listowel-shannon-river-ferry-lahinch-sunday-lunch-cliffs-of-moher-live-music-at-doolinrimage/</guid><description>it’s sunday. our last night at the ballygarry house hotel was quiet for a change, which is nice. also, as long as our group is having breakfast, we are spared the rather annoying radio blast.1
after breakfast mrs d and i pack our stuff and join the rest of the pilgrims in our pilgrims bus. the first stop today is in listowel — apparently the literary capital of ireland. our stop is short: mr tambour, our pilgrimage guide, as always, is extremely well prepared and we learn quite a bit about listowel and its literary sons and daughters — but also take a look at listowel’s racetrack during the bus ride from tralee to listowel a co-pilgrim mentioned that apparently writers with a residence in ireland would live tax-free: might that explain the relatively high percentage of writers in relation to the total population?</description></item><item><title>brendan’s chapel, an daingean, gallarus oratory, an inch of beach</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-18-brendans-chapel-an-daingean-gallarus-oratory-an-inch-of-beach/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 20:10:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-18-brendans-chapel-an-daingean-gallarus-oratory-an-inch-of-beach/</guid><description>our final full day at tralee and the ballygarry house hotel. tonight we are spared the noisy party guests, unfortunately other co-pilgrims are not so lucky, they suffer from a rather rowdy crowd leaving this night’s wedding party at about 4:00 in the morning. the lady at reception kind of just shrugs her shoulders and replies that it’s not their fault — which ticks me off into voicing my disagreement with that statement…to little avail as her reply is that “they were celebrating a wedding“.</description></item><item><title>gap of dunloe &amp; the lakes of killarney</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-17-gap-of-dunloe-the-lakes-of-killarney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 18:26:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-17-gap-of-dunloe-the-lakes-of-killarney/</guid><description>breakfast today (we are still at the ballygarry house hotel) works out a bit better than yesterday: more coffee and tea available, no being told off for sitting at the wrong table. today’s program: by bus to the starting point of the pass up to the gap of dunloe, walk from there over the gap of dunloe and down to brandon’s cottage for a cup of tea, followed by a boat trip across the lakes of killarney to the town of killarney.</description></item><item><title>brandon’s well, an daingean peninsula</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-16-brandons-well-an-daingean-peninsula/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 17:28:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-16-brandons-well-an-daingean-peninsula/</guid><description>around 2:00 in the morning: a group of hotel guests from that anniversary party very kindly let us in into their conversations they are having in the parking lot outside the hotel entrance — for about half an hour we get to share each and every attempt at jokularity… much appreciated.
at breakfast mrs d and i commit the faux pas of seating ourselves at one of the free tables as the large group table seems to be fully occupied.</description></item><item><title>a new breakfast beverage, brigid’s well, rock of cashel</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-15-a-new-breakfast-beverage-brigids-well-rock-of-cashel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 20:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-15-a-new-breakfast-beverage-brigids-well-rock-of-cashel/</guid><description>no “madame–baby” wake-up call this morning (i guess mr charming realized that madame was already taking a shower when he called) but a bit of re-packing before breakfast as today we are relocating to tralee in county kerry. having learnt from yesterday’s breakfast i appear on the scene 15min early and order coffee (for me) and tea (for mrs d) along with my cooked breakfast — ms rough charme tries to force me to use the german breakfast menu but i stubbornly insists on using the original.</description></item><item><title>oh, look, rain!…kevin’s way…glendalough</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-14-oh-look-rain-kevins-way-glendalough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 20:19:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-14-oh-look-rain-kevins-way-glendalough/</guid><description>ring, ring — mrs d picks up the phone, it’s the 7:15 wake-up call and, as expected, nobody answers back. time to get up. ring, ring — mrs d picks up the phone yet again, this time round it’s the bloke from reception asking whether “madame is ok?”, madame affirms and receives a rather charming “ok, baby”. this somewhat incongruous start into our first day as pilgrims in ireland kind of forms the fabric of the day: it stays incongruous, constantly changing between dry and rather wet.</description></item><item><title>on an irish pilgrimage…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-13-on-an-irish-pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 20:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-13-on-an-irish-pilgrimage/</guid><description>the next 10 days we are taking part in a spiritual journey through ireland. really kind of a pilgrimage, a christian pilgrimage to be precise, by bus (not a lot of walking involved, unfortunately) to the places of the old, celtic irish church. the whole trip has been organized by the akademie st. paul — and it’s the first group trip of this kind that i’ve ever participated in and i’m not too sure whether it’s going to be to my liking.</description></item><item><title>more vincent stuff…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-11-more-vincent-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-11-more-vincent-stuff/</guid><description>looking through drscofield’s twitter messages of the past couple of days i noticed @pixelq’s twitter about “watching the world” and i had to head over to youtube to watch this 3D internet masterpiece once more. IMHO it’s one of the most beautiful pieces of art (and it’s a pity it wasn’t on display in basel recently) — have a look yourself:
almost makes you cry…
content.</description></item><item><title>felsenputzing, take 2</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-05-felsenputzing-take-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2009 17:28:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-05-felsenputzing-take-2/</guid><description>if you thought my post about felsenputzing was a joke, think again. courtesy of avid tagesanzeiger reader, mrs d, the link for all of you who want to become expert felsenputzer: register here.</description></item><item><title>having a look at vincent’s pictures</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-21-having-a-look-at-vincents-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 18:54:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-21-having-a-look-at-vincents-pictures/</guid><description>the kunstmuseum in basel is hosting an exhibition of vincent van gogh’s landscape pictures and we had been planning on going up to basel and having a look at them. so, as this sunday had more or less non-stop rain forecast, we had an early sunday breakfast, skipped church, grabbed our rail network cards and hopped on the train from einsiedeln to wädenswil, and changed into the IR train to basel.</description></item><item><title>16:00 back in einsiedeln</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-1600-back-in-einsiedeln/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 20:34:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-1600-back-in-einsiedeln/</guid><description>at lucerne verkehrshaus i disembark one station earlier than planned, trying to catch the voralpenexpress train back to biberbrugg. with a bit of, let’s say, fast-hobbling i manage to catch the train and am on my way back home.
at biberbrugg i meet up with mrs d who has just been dropped of by fredi and is tired but happy from a fantastic day out. together we hop on to the train to einsiedeln and walk/hobble home picture links:</description></item><item><title>middle of lake lucerne, 14:00</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-middle-of-lake-lucerne-1400/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 17:09:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-middle-of-lake-lucerne-1400/</guid><description>the post bus ride from ibergeregg pass down to schwyz was, well, exciting if not adventurous. in contrast to the more gentle norther approach from oberiberg, the southern approach really takes you into the alps with breathtaking views across lake lucerne, up to the huser stock and hengst mountains — all the way constantly going back and forth, left and right, most of the time with no space for two cars, let alone a car and post bus, to pass each other.</description></item><item><title>ibergeregg pass, 10:20</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-ibergeregg-pass-1020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 08:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-ibergeregg-pass-1020/</guid><description>first stop on my tour through the swiss alps by public transport: ibergeregg pass.
the post bus from oberiberg wound its way up the pass road navigating lots of curves and bends each time sounding its characteristic swiss post bus horn: dah-dee-doh-dah!
this text will be replaced
var so = new SWFObject('/embed/jw/player.swf',&amp;lsquo;mpl&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;470&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;20&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;9&amp;rsquo;); so.addParam(&amp;lsquo;allowscriptaccess&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;always&amp;rsquo;); so.addParam(&amp;lsquo;allowfullscreen&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;true&amp;rsquo;); so.addParam(&amp;lsquo;flashvars&amp;rsquo;,'&amp;amp;author=dirk husemann&amp;amp;description=post bus horn of the ibergeregg - schwyz post bus&amp;amp;duration=7&amp;amp;file=http://d2h.net/blog/stuff/postbus.mp3&amp;amp;title=post bus horn concerto'); so.write(&amp;lsquo;playerpostbus&amp;rsquo;);
sound of the ibergeregg–schwyz post bus</description></item><item><title>einsiedeln, 9:05</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-einsiedeln-905/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 07:05:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-06-01-einsiedeln-905/</guid><description>having hobbled to einsiedeln station, i’m in time for the 9:05 post bus to oberiberg — the weather is fantastic and i do envy mrs d for her snowshoe hike from the gotthard pass up to fibbia, a tour i’d been looking forward to very much1, especially as it is guided by fredi kälin from bluedimensions (if you want to do really nice walks or snowshoe tours: book fredi!)
instead of moapping around at home, however, i’ve planned a little mountain and lake tour myself — using only public transport i intend to go from einsiedeln via oberiberg to ibergeregg pass, have a coffee break there and enjoy the panorama, then on to the capital of our canton, schwyz.</description></item><item><title>groundforce afternoon</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-05-30-groundforce-afternoon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 20:11:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-05-30-groundforce-afternoon/</guid><description>originally our plans for the pentecost weekend had been to do a two day walk in the napf area, a rather nice walking area between lucerne and berne. originally…
well, two weeks ago we set out to find the “across einsiedeln” geocache — which was supposed to be a rather simple one in easy terrain. as the weather was quite warm i didn’t put on my mountain boots but instead went in sandals — had i but known… we did find the GPS location of the “across einsiedeln” geocache, but didn’t find the cache itself.</description></item><item><title>in bed with flu...</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-02-09-flue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-02-09-flue/</guid><description>since monday afternoon i’m in bed with flu. not particularly pleasant. fever wouldn’t retreat really until yesterday evening. went to see my very capable physician yesterday who did a very thorough check including a CRP blood test, all in all, revealing that i was probably suffering from a viral infection but on the way back to the living again. he told me to stay at home until friday (which i’m doing).</description></item><item><title>clonetowns</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-30-clonetowns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-30-clonetowns/</guid><description>just watched BBC1’s insideout, especially a feature about the “development” of london’s portobello road. “development” in quotes because it’s really about driving out old, established small shops and businesses to increase the yield through rents that are 100% higher and can only be afforded by the big chain stores (just noticed that my hands wanted to write “chain saws”…fitting, though, as these chain stores just mercilessly cut through established societal fabrics, destroying local culture and colour wherever they appear).</description></item><item><title>tracking suits...</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-30-suitsat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-30-suitsat/</guid><description>no, i didn’t mean to write “track suit” :-) the astronauts on the ISS will be releasing a used astronaut’s spacesuit filled with a radio and sensors into orbit. according to NASA’s suitsat page explains how the russian cosmonauts came up with the idea of stuffing “three batteries, a radio transmitter, and internal sensors to measure temperature and battery power” into used (and, one assumes, retired) spacesuits. using a police scanner (hmm, now, who’d have one of those?</description></item><item><title>growing grass on jute bags</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-28-tr-bags/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-28-tr-bags/</guid><description>just read an article in the german edition of february’s technology review about the work of harmut koehler on the revitec(tm) project. the revitec project tries to stop and reverse desertification by using jute bags (recycled coffee bean bags, bremen is one of the major german coffee importing and processing ports) filled with sand, compost and other organic material. the jute bags are then used as “breeding ground” for weeds, grass, and even tree.</description></item><item><title>worship service in erlangen</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-22-worship-service-erlangen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-22-worship-service-erlangen/</guid><description>this morning had us a bit worked up: we had planned and then this morning led through today’s worship service at our baptist church here in erlangen. all a bit exciting and we certainly had a bout of stage fever. everything worked out fine and even the sermon was well received (sigh of relief :-)
over lunch we were invited by friends, which we enjoyed very much. the rest of the afternoon is spent working on the missing pictures of last thursday, friday, saturday, and sunday… (you might notice that saturday’s picture technically is not really saturday’s picture: the date &amp;amp; time recorded in it’s EXIF data is already past midnight and would thus indicate that it’s been taken on sunday already: not so, the clock on my digital camera is still running on summer time [and i can’t be bothered to switch it, not with another summer time rushing towards us]).</description></item><item><title>zur sonne brüder, zum licht! (a trip to zugerberg)</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-08-zugerberg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-08-zugerberg/</guid><description>it’s sunday…yesterday we attended a full day workshop on “aufatmen und frei sein” (roughly translated as “breath again and be free”) which was organized by the united methodist church of switzerland and took place in zurich. it was rather refreshing and provided lots of encouragement not only to take a positive, christian view of the world but also to try and make a difference in other people’s lives. the workshop was done by robert seitz (contributing excellent texts, giving much food for thought) and christof fankhauser (accentuating and amplifying seitz’s texts through his musical meditations and songs).</description></item><item><title>welcome to 2006!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-01-happy-new-year/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2006-01-01-happy-new-year/</guid><description>a happy &amp;amp; blessed 2006 to you all!
on 21 december spiegel online had an article about a young photographer, lisa frischemeier, who had done a rather interesting project in 2005: she’d taken and published one picture a day every day in 2005! quite a challenge…but worth the try. above is my first. taken on the way from church to the railway station (getting tickets back to zürich for tomorrow).</description></item><item><title>isle of wight to erlangen...by train</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-30-bahn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-30-bahn/</guid><description>while discussing travel arrangements for next years vacation in england (london &amp;amp; the isle of wight) we wondered whether it would be possible to get from the isle of wight (ryde, to be precise) to erlangen in one day…by train! to make it more interesting, we didn’t want to get up in the middle of the night, so a decent departure time, like 9 o’clock was desired…
so, off we go and ask the european train timetable oracle…which to our immense surprise returns the following schedule:</description></item><item><title>a podcast christmas carol...</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-17-christmas-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-17-christmas-podcast/</guid><description>from the 1950s back to the future: len and nora from jawboneradio have an interesting link to “a podcast christmas carol”, a podcast adaptatation of charles dickens’s christmas book a christmas carol into our times and a into a podcast featuring podcaster from around the world.
sounds interesting. let’s see how that is going to turn out :-)</description></item><item><title>stop press: WDR recovers web pages from 1956...</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-17-wdr-1956/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-17-wdr-1956/</guid><description>[the following article is rated SGR (some german required)]
just saw the link on spiegel online about the west german radio station WDR recovering their 1956 web site from their archives!
excellent archaeological work! they managed to completely restore their vintage 1956 web site. i particularly like the tv programme section:
on sunday, 1 january 1956 they had only three (3) broadcasts, while on monday, 2 january 1956 they had an almost full programme with a rocking 9 broadcasts and a “switch-over at 21:25” (whatever that was).</description></item><item><title>walking over dead bodies...or: a wimpy terminator</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-14-walking-over-dead-bodies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-12-14-walking-over-dead-bodies/</guid><description>quite sad to read about the execution of tookie william last night. the common view by commentators seems to be that california’s governor, arnold schwarzenegger, did not grant clemency because of not wanting to his republican clientel to appear soft on crime — and in particular wanted to boost his image after having lost several referendums and elections in the last months.
mr william has been in prison for such a long time that in other, civilized, countries he’d have served a life sentence already.</description></item><item><title>så som i himmelen...as it is in heaven</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-11-20-sa-som-i-himmelen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-11-20-sa-som-i-himmelen/</guid><description>what’s happened to us? another night at the movies! a colleague from germany had recommended wie im himmel (english title: as it is in heaven)…at first it seemed a bit brutal, to say the least, and i was wondering about my colleague’s taste — but once the real action starts (daniel returning back to the village where he was born) the movie starts to really unfold and takes you on an emotional roller-coaster-ride — and has some very pointed dialogues about living one’s life instead of being lived and instead of being locked in by we’ve-always-done-it-this-way-no-need-to-change-it-now-or-ever.</description></item><item><title>20 years later...</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-11-12-20yearslater/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-11-12-20yearslater/</guid><description>we’ve been in northern germany back at my parents place over the weekend, taking the 9:01 train from erlangen to nürnberg, then the 9:39 ICE to hannover, and finally the 12:45 from hannover to delmenhorst — where we are picked up by my father and given a lift to my parents place in hoykenkamp.
the reason for our trip north: the 20th anniversary of my “abitur” (i.e., high school graduation or GCE-A levels) class.</description></item><item><title>let's buy some autobahn</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-16-buying-autobahn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-16-buying-autobahn/</guid><description>today’s spiegel online reports that the probably soon to be german finance minister peer steinbrück plans to sell off germany’s autobahns to close gaping canyons in the german budget.
interesting. how much is a piece of autobahn then? according to the article the lowest estimate is a whooping (or not so whooping) €127’000’000’000 for all of the roughly 12’000km of german autobahn. which, more or less, comes down to €10’584/m.</description></item><item><title>gregorian music</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-13-gregorian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-13-gregorian/</guid><description>have been listening to gregorian music all day during work: kind of soothing &amp;amp; calming in its simplicity…bought them all at audiolunchbox (another music service “that get’s it”).</description></item><item><title>die grosse stille...into great silence</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-11-die-grosse-stille/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-11-die-grosse-stille/</guid><description>went out tonight to watch a movie — which in itself is rare, as we rather watch “new” movies on DVD at home than go and sit with 50, 100, or even 200 other people in a more or less (un)comfortable seat, with a guaranteed tall person to come in at the last minute and take the seat(s) in front of you.
what was unusual about this movie was that it was shown inside the university church, the neustädter kirche, that it was shown using digital projection (not a beamer!</description></item><item><title>speeding across lake constance</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-02-zeppelin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-02-zeppelin/</guid><description>rainy sunday…take the s-bahn from mannenbach to kreuzlingen and thence to konstanz. continue on to friedrichshafen by the newly installed katamaran service. the trip is quite nice, quite a number of passengers on the kat, but not too many :-)
we arrive around 12:00 in friedrichshafen, almost right at the entrance of the zeppelin museum, our destination for today. inside we are at first quite surprised to see long queues but then remember that is fall vacation time, it’s raining, so what do you do when you’ve got a bunch of kids to entertain?</description></item><item><title>oh, look! a lake!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-01-mannenbach/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2005-10-01-mannenbach/</guid><description>up at 7:15, getting everything cleaned up and in ship shape…9:01, we take the RE train from erlangen to nürnberg, then the IC train from nürnberg to stuttgart, switch there to the ICE to schaffhausen and then the S bahn train to mannenbach-saalenstein…we arrive on time in mannenbach-saalenstein
our hotel, the seehotel schiff, is literally just around the corner from the railway station and only a 3min walk. it’s located directly at the shore of the bodensee (“lake constance”) — and from our room at the top of the hotel we have a very nice view across to reichenau and across the lower bodensee to radolfzell.</description></item></channel></rss>