<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>d2h.net: flotsam, jetsam, &amp; lagan</title><link>https://d2h.net/</link><description>Recent content on d2h.net: flotsam, jetsam, &amp; lagan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Dirk Husemann — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 21:17:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d2h.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>githubbing</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2022-01-19-githubbing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 21:17:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2022-01-19-githubbing/</guid><description>I recently read the excellent essay my first impressions of web3 by moxie marlinspike, and one of the observations he is making is1
People don’t want to run their own servers, and never will.
Running your own server is fun and very instructional &amp;mdash; for geeks like us…
…for a time…
…after about 20 years or so you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it all, done it all, tried it all, met all the script kiddies in your logs, evaded them by moving your SSH server port out of harm&amp;rsquo;s way (not that you were using password-based ssh accounts to begin with, it was just so annoying to see them try the same thing over and over again, no creativity really, come on…), dito for the attack attempts on your nginx server (again, easily foiled, by using a handful of fail2ban rules).</description></item><item><title>About…</title><link>https://d2h.net/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:07:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/about/</guid><description>Welcome to my blog, d2h.net. Here you will stuff that I find interesting, useful, or noteworthy for some reason or other &amp;mdash; in short, stuff the cat dragged in, or the sea delivered to our doorsteps.
This blog is built using
hugo, emacs, a derivative of the smigle hugo theme, the computer modern typewriter font, and the special elite typewriter font, and is hosted via github.
Responsible contact:</description></item><item><title>building emacs for macos</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-12-27-emacs-for-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 14:53:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-12-27-emacs-for-macos/</guid><description>my copy of emacs installed through homebrew was acting up: everytime i tried to click the &amp;ldquo;markdown&amp;rdquo; menu when editing a markdown&amp;rsquo;ed text file, emacs would terminate rather abruptly (aka crash). decidedly not nice.
so: try to reinstall… a couple of hours later this is the recipe that worked for me:
&amp;gt; brew install --with-modern-icon --without-spacemacs-icon --with-mailutils --with-jansson --HEAD emacs-plus followed by
option-cmd dragging the generated /usr/local/opt/emacs-plus/Emacs.app to /Applications, and allowing Emacs full-disk access macos security setings for emacs</description></item><item><title>automated hugo</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-06-14-gitea-drone-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 08:26:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-06-14-gitea-drone-hugo/</guid><description>Inspired by Evan Brown&amp;rsquo;s post Hugo on the go I decided to follow pretty much the same route &amp;mdash; with a couple of twists.
In a nutshell Evan has set up a continuous integration chain for his hugo based website. The workflow is as follows:
create the new hugo post on whatever device you want commit the post and push to github github triggers the continuous integration service travis travis regenerates the static web site travis deploys the static web site Where Evan is using github, travis, and S3 I wanted to go the self-hosted route.</description></item><item><title>Full Circle</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-05-19-switching-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 16:53:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2019-05-19-switching-to-hugo/</guid><description>OK, I&amp;rsquo;m back to where I started, blog-wise: statically generated content. The first incarnation of d2h.net was using an emacs generated blog, this time round I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with using hugo.
The workflow is a bit different now from back then: content is contained in a self-hosted gitea instance, which is feeding into a self-hosted drone instance, all docker-ized.
The hugo theme is not quite there yet, expect changes 😀</description></item><item><title>shipping forecast</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-03-07-shipping-forecast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 22:31:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-03-07-shipping-forecast/</guid><description>having just updated our squeezebox radios i re-found the BBC iplayer plugin. it’s been lingering in depths of the squeezebox radio menus for ages, i guess, but i had never really checked it out. while waiting for @jmdhh to return i decided to give the iplayer plugin a spin.
for some reasons i narrowed in on BBC4 and encountered old friends such as “the now show” (which i regularly listen to via their podcast) or less known shows such as the intriguingly named “life: an idiot’s guide” (need to check that one out).</description></item><item><title>a time trip to the 1950s</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-22-a-time-trip-to-the-1950s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 14:58:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-22-a-time-trip-to-the-1950s/</guid><description>even though the place we live at here in switzerland has a rather rural character — there are several livestock markets throughout the year down at the station square, very few regions regularly vote more conservative than ours — einsiedeln has a surprising cultural live. one of the driving forces is the chaernehus, which several times a year hosts cabaret, an exhibition, and stages a play.
this year’s play is kino etzel — which @jmdhh and i went to see tonight.</description></item><item><title>smells &amp; memory</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-16-smells-memory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 23:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-16-smells-memory/</guid><description>the other day @jmdhh and i were out shopping. while i was waiting at one of the shops i was “hit” by a smell of coffee — and immediately taken back to the apartment of my grandmother in the late 60s, early 70s. she lived in bremerhaven, one of the german sea ports, and had a penchant for coffee.
her apartment always smelled of coffee in a certain way — the smell of coffee emanating from that shop at which i was waiting for @jmdhh must have hit my olfactory memory at just the right spot and triggered that flashback to my childhood.</description></item><item><title>recipe: slow-roasted pork butt (blade)</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-07-recipe-slow-roasted-pork-butt-blade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 19:10:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-07-recipe-slow-roasted-pork-butt-blade/</guid><description>meat:
1kg pork butt (blade) crust:
1 glove garlic teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons italian herb mixture 1 teaspoon sweet paprika 3 tablespoons olive oil freshly ground pepper 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar (aceto balsamico) pre-heat the oven to 80–90°C
wash the pork and dry it with kitchen tissue. incise the pork butt all around in a diagonally criss-crossing pattern.
strip the garlic glove, place it together with the teaspoon of salt in a mortar and crush it with the pestle until you end up with a smooth paste.</description></item><item><title>the joys of creative commons licenses</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-02-the-joys-of-creative-commons-licenses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 15:36:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2012-01-02-the-joys-of-creative-commons-licenses/</guid><description>i’m in the process of re-working both this blog and my photo site. for the photo site i’ve switched from zenphoto to jalbum — zenphoto didn’t really offer any decent support for displaying geo-tagged pictures, had at the point in time of switching too many security issues for my taste, and didn’t have such a slick looking theme as jalbum’s turtle skin.
for a couple of sub-albums i wanted to make use of the background music feature offered by the turtle skin.</description></item><item><title>@jmdhh admiring the views…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-07-05-jmdhh-admiring-the-views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 18:57:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-07-05-jmdhh-admiring-the-views/</guid><description>at the beginning of june @jmdhh and i spent two fantastic weeks in the english lake district — one of our walks took us up on top of silver how. the photo below shows @jmdhh enjoying the wonderful landscape and views, all of them at once it seems.
jQuery(document).ready(function(){jQuery(&amp;quot;#848a11e54a625663&amp;quot;).photoNav({id:&amp;ldquo;848a11e54a625663&amp;rdquo;,mode:&amp;ldquo;drag&amp;rdquo;,popup:&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo;,animate:&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;});});</description></item><item><title>recipe: vampire ears tortilla with cherry tomato chutney</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-06-13-recipe-vampire-ears-tortilla-with-cherry-tomato-chutney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 19:22:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-06-13-recipe-vampire-ears-tortilla-with-cherry-tomato-chutney/</guid><description>tortilla1 ingredients:
300g potatoes 140g dried tomatoes in olive oil (aka vampire ears) 40g pitted black olives 5 large eggs clove of garlic 2 + 1 tablespoons olive oil chutney ingredients:
200g cherry tomatoes 1 tablespoon olive oil 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar 1/2 teaspoon sage 2 pinches basil 1 pinch sugar salt pepper start with making the chutney: wash the cherry tomatoes and quarter them. heat the olive oil in a small pan and add the quartered tomatoes, then add the rest of the ingredients.</description></item><item><title>panorama picture experiment</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-01-03-panorama-picture-experiment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 19:16:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2011-01-03-panorama-picture-experiment/</guid><description>last saturday mrs d and i did a snow shoe hike from alpthal stei up to hochstuckli and then across to biberegg. the views were fantastic, the snow was good prompted by mrs d, i tried my hand at taking a set of pictures to assemble as a panorama later.1 here’s the result (you can use the mouse to drag the picture around):
jQuery(document).ready(function(){jQuery(&amp;quot;#cd03e9de8d63dba5&amp;quot;).photoNav({id:&amp;ldquo;cd03e9de8d63dba5&amp;rdquo;,mode:&amp;ldquo;drag&amp;rdquo;,popup:&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo;,animate:&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;});});
i stitched it together using hugin — i’m quite pleased with it let’s see how it turns out as a 120cm wide print.</description></item><item><title>some more pseudo HDR experiments</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-31-some-more-pseudo-hdr-experiments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 07:46:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-31-some-more-pseudo-hdr-experiments/</guid><description>during sunday’s #twallfahrt i managed to take a couple of 5-step bracketed pictures, two of which i think produced some interesting results. the first one is the view from etzel pass towards einsiedeln:
at first i thought that it looks a bit weird, then i realized (and on my way home looked at the clouds with “different eyes”) that it does look like that.
the second one is a classical, an in-door shot in the church of the monastery of einsiedeln1:</description></item><item><title>world’s first twitter wallfahrt!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-29-worlds-first-twitter-wallfahrt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 20:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-29-worlds-first-twitter-wallfahrt/</guid><description>9:10 — ms d and i arrive at einsiedeln railway station, all kitted out in our walking gear, ready to go. walking past the train we spot our fellow pilgrims. yep, pilgrims: we are on our way to the starting point of the world’s first twitter pilgrimage, the #twallfahrt1 from pfäffikon to einsiedeln. in the train we meet @decolores1, @konzertharfe, @sempreincorsaa also ready to go on the #twallfahrt. just before the train is about to depart at 9:13 we are joined at the last second by @abtmartin — good thing, too, as he is supposed to lead us on our pilgrimage i’m looking forward to the first twitter pilgrimage which is at the same time my first pilgrimage on foot (last year’s pilgrimage was by bus, which somehow gives it a different twist, i think).</description></item><item><title>mucking around with pseudo HDRs</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-28-mucking-around-with-pseudo-hdrs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 19:53:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-08-28-mucking-around-with-pseudo-hdrs/</guid><description>it’s taken a long time, but i finally managed to upload the pictures of our lake district vacation (back in may, yes…) to our photo website, the 50mm-traveller. for most of the pictures i used the exposure bracketing mode of my D700 (i.e., one picture taken at normal exposure, one a full stop below and the third a full stop above) together with the high-speed setting (5 pictures per second).</description></item><item><title>swiss conservatives: annex regions surrounding switzerland!</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-06-12-swiss-conservatives-annex-regions-surrounding-switzerland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 09:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-06-12-swiss-conservatives-annex-regions-surrounding-switzerland/</guid><description>yesterday’s tagesanzeiger report on a parliamentary motion of the swiss conservatives right-wing, nationalist party SVP to prepare the annexation of all regions surrounding switzerland — no, today’s not the first of april.
interesting.
as the tagesanzeiger rightly observes that would add about 10 million germans to the population (plus almost another million german speaking citizens of alsace, vorarlberg, &amp;amp; bolzano) — just a couple of months ago the SVP, never afraid of playing the lowest available instruments of fear, uncertainty, and doubt, staged a campaign claiming that the ETH was being overtaken by german professors (skillfully representing sliced statistics to “prove” their point).</description></item><item><title>how my grandfather created an island…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-16-how-my-grandfather-created-an-island/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 18:24:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-16-how-my-grandfather-created-an-island/</guid><description>my grandfather was a sea-faring man.1
my grandfather was a sea-faring man, and, what is more, he helped create an island… an island that is still visible today.
he was employed by the North German Lloyd aka Norddeutscher Lloyd as an officer, his last ship was the steamship goslar. shortly before the outbreak of world war II the goslar was on its way back to germany and had just passed the panama canal when adolf the terrible declared war on poland.</description></item><item><title>in the lake district again…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-09-in-the-lake-district-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 20:26:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2010-05-09-in-the-lake-district-again/</guid><description>after a long day on the train — starting with the 8:43 ICE International train from cologne to brussels, then the Eurostar to london st pancras, followed by the virgin pendolino from london euston (yep, a short walk from there) to oxenholme lake district, and, the last train for today, the First Penine 185 class service to windermere — we have finally arrived at the riverside hotel in ambleside.
the riverside is a small hotel run by david and brenda milne a bit outside ambleside, right next to the river rothay on the quiet under loughrigg lane leading from ambleside to rydal.</description></item><item><title>switzerland — behind the scenes…</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-12-29-switzerland-behind-the-scenes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 21:07:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-12-29-switzerland-behind-the-scenes/</guid><description>ever wondered what happens behind the scenes of touristic switzerland? ever wanted to know how the swiss manage to present one of the most beautiful places on earth in such impeccable order? ever interested in the music that drives the swiss?1
wonder no more: here’s a rare behind the scenes look at switzerland:
now you know the true story… well, some of them… ↩</description></item><item><title>d2h.net now mobile friendly</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-d2h-net-now-mobile-friendly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 20:43:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-d2h-net-now-mobile-friendly/</guid><description>thanks to the excellent wordpress mobile pack wordpress plugin i’m pleased to announce that d2h.net is now mobile enabled: if you visit it on your android or iDon’t, err, iPhone you’ll get a mobile browser-friendly version of our web site. also, http://m.d2h.net/ will take you to the mobile version directly as well.
oh, and you might have noticed, i’ve re-organized the site structure slightly, the blog is now directly at the root of the site.</description></item><item><title>friday evening rucola salmon salad</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-friday-evening-rucola-salmon-salad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-10-24-friday-evening-rucola-salmon-salad/</guid><description>easy salad:
about 125g rucola leaves about 80-100g smoked salmon 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 teaspoons of whole-grained mustard salt lemon juice cut or shred the salmon into little pieces. wash the rucola leaves in a colander and shake off the excessive water. mix the rucola, and the salmon pieces in a bowl. add the oil and the mustard along with a couple of squirts of the lemon juice.</description></item><item><title>kells, tara, airport, trinity college, chilling out</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-22-kells-tara-airport-trinity-college-chilling-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 20:58:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-22-kells-tara-airport-trinity-college-chilling-out/</guid><description>the last day of our irish pilgrimage! after another good breakfast at the newgrange hotel we pack once more and enter our pilgrims bus — which this morning has grown in size: morris, our excellent driver, swapped our smaller bus yesterday evening for a bigger one as he’s going to pick up a group of 50 at dublin airport right after dropping us off.
the final “building blocks” of our pilgrimage are kells and the hill of tara.</description></item><item><title>a walk through pittoresque boyne valley, time travel, monasterboice, &amp; the hill of slane</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-21-a-walk-through-pittoresque-boyne-valley-time-travel-monasterboice-slaine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 20:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-21-a-walk-through-pittoresque-boyne-valley-time-travel-monasterboice-slaine/</guid><description>mrs d and i slept surprisingly well this night, given the fact that one of the main thorough-fares passes the hotel just a couple of meters away.1 breakfast is efficient and good and the waitresses are actually quite friendly and even know about gluten-free food for mrs j.2
the weather has become rather irish: it’s raining when we set off for a walk in the boyne valley, and it’s treating us to several showers on the otherwise rather pittoresque walk.</description></item><item><title>the burren, limestone pavement, clonmacnoise, &amp; an almost secret birthday</title><link>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-20-limestone-pavement-an-almost-secret-birthday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 20:21:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d2h.net/posts/2009-07-20-limestone-pavement-an-almost-secret-birthday/</guid><description>after a rather good night and an equally good and relaxed breakfast1 at hotel doolin we pack once more and embark on the long trip across ireland, going from the atlantic west coast all the way to navan. the weather is not as good as it was yesterday with clouds covering most of the sky.
we don’t just go to navan directly but instead take the scenic route. our first stop is at burren national park, the smallest of the 6 national parks in ireland and part of the larger area the burren: a karst landscape exhibiting the typical karst limestone pavement and also host for a number of megalithic tombs and portal dolmens — rather impressive.</description></item></channel></rss>